George E. Agree Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
George E. Agree Papers 1961-2001
MSS85335
Agree, George E.
1,000 items 2 containers .8 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Author and political scientist. Correspondence, minutes, press material, reports, and writings relating to Agree’s work as president of the American Political Foundation, executive director of the National Committee for an Effective Congress, and involvement in other political groups.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Agree, George E.
Organizations
American Political Foundation.; National Committee for an Effective Congress.; National Endowment for Democracy (U.S.); United States. Congress.
Subjects
Campaign funds--United States.; Democracy.; Political science--United States.; World politics--20th century.
Places
United States--Politics and government--20th century.
Occupations
Authors.; Political scientists.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The papers of George E. Agree, author and political scientist, were given to the Library of Congress by his wife, Lee Agree, in 2006.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of George E. Agree are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1921, June 25 Born, New York, N.Y.
1942 B.A., University of California, Los Angeles, Calif.
1942-1945 Sergeant, U. S. Army Air Corps weather service
1946-1947 Lobbyist, American League for a Free Palestine
1952-1966 Director, National Committee for an Effective Congress
1963-1964 Director, Republican Legislative Research Association
1966-1967 Associate, Stephen R. Currier
1967-2001 Director, Committee for the Democratic Process
1968-1974 Director and fund-raiser, Campaign Funds (1968, 1970, 1972, 1974)
1971-1974 Director, Twentieth Century Fund Study of Political Finance
1975 Published with David W. Adamany Political Money; A Strategy for Campaign Financing in America. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press
1976-1979 Consultant, campaign finance reforms
1980-1984 President, American Political Foundation
1985-1988 Director, foreign programs, Former Members of Congress
1989-2001 Executive director, Institute for Representative Government
2001, Dec. 11 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of George E. Agree (1921-2001) span the years 1961-2001 and consist of congressional testimony, correspondence, minutes, press material, reports, and writings pertaining to Agree’s career as a political scientist. The collection documents Agree’s involvement in the American Political Foundation, the National Committee for an Effective Congress, and the National Endowment for Democracy. Additional material covers Agree’s work on election campaign finance reform, including several articles he authored on the subject. Miscellaneous material includes biographical information, proposals, and writings.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged alphabetically by topic.
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm2006085335
Container List
- American Politicial Foundation (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1983, undated (Box 1)
  - Incorporation, 1980-1983 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1979-1983 (Box 1)
  - Press, 1979-1984, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Reports and proposals, 1977-1983, undated (Box 1)
  - Travel itineraries, 1979-1980, undated (Box 1)
- Campaign finance reform (Box 1)
  - American Bar Association symposium, Tiburon, Calif., 1974-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Articles by Agree, 1974-1983, undated (Box 2)
  - Press, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Senate Committee on Finance hearings, 1967-1977, (2 folders) (Box 2)
- National Committee for an Effective Congress, 1961-1968, 1975-1978, (2 folders) (Box 2)
- National Endowment for Democracy, 1983, 1994 (Box 2)
- Miscellany, 1967-1979, 2001 (Box 2)